<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
 	<channel>
		<title>Dan Wood: The Eponymous Blog</title>
		<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/</link>
		<description></description>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 09:56:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
		<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
		<generator>Sandvox 2.10.6</generator>
		<item>
			<title>East Bay Mini Maker Faire</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/east-bay-mini-maker-faire.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been going to the &lt;a href="http://makerfaire.com/"&gt;Maker Faire&lt;/a&gt; on and off over the years since it first started in 2006. The original one in San Mateo is spectacular, but it has gotten so big and crowded in the past few years that it’s just not as enjoyable to me anymore as it was before it got super-crowded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;a href="https://ebmakerfaire.wordpress.com/"&gt;East Bay Mini Maker Faire&lt;/a&gt;, which just happened last weekend? Just the right size. Community-sized, and if you live in the area, there’s a good chance you will run into more than one maker or attendee that you know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At last weekend’s event, I got to wear a “Maker” badge for the first time. I was helping the &lt;a href="http://alamedabees.org/"&gt;Alameda County Beekeepers Association&lt;/a&gt;, showing off a demonstration hive to visitors, answering questions, giving advice, and occasionally selling a jar of &lt;a href="http://sweethomealameda.com/"&gt;honey that came from my bees&lt;/a&gt; or from one of the other booth volunteer’s beehives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is being a beekeeper really being a “maker” in the strictest sense of the word? Sometimes I would ask children at the booth just &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; were the makers at our booth, and they would invariably point to the bees. So, tongue in cheek, I covered up the “M” on my badge and hand-drew the letter “T” so it read TAKER.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if I’m merely taking care of the bees and collecting their excess honey from time to time, it’s an activity that I enjoy becuase it’s doing something in the real world, not the virtual world of websites and programming. It’s a nice occasional break from my “day job” to check on the hives, collect honey, rescue a springtime swarm, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/bee-emerging-from-cell_med.jpeg" alt="bee emerging from cell" width="206" height="310" class="first narrow right graphic-container" /&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Truly the best part of my experience at the beekeeper’s booth this last weekend was talking to the kids who came up to see what was going on. They all had lots of questions, and many of them were starting from a good foundation of knowledge. (Are you having problems with hives dying out? Is the queen here in this hive? etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every kid — and just about every adult — who saw what I pointed out in the demonstration hive was excited and fascinated. The frames that could be seen thorugh the plexiglass were covered with brood (egg) cells, and throughout the day, it was pretty easy to notice a few “new bees” starting to hatch out of their cells. Maybe you could just barely see the antennae wingling out from a chewed-open hole in the cell, or maybe the bee had gotten its entire head out and was slowly emerging. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/8je59t"&gt;Photo CC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;If you live near a Maker Faire — one of the main ones or a “mini” maker faire, I can’t recommend strongly enough that you check one out. &lt;a href="http://makerfaire.com/map/"&gt;They are happening all over the world.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 20:01:23 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/east-bay-mini-maker-faire.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Desire for streets that accomodate cyclists and pedestrians in my town seems to be outpacing the backlash to modest improvements</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/pedestrian-cyclist-petition.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, bicycling and pedestrian advocates in the town where I live have been managing to make a bit of headway in an otherwise car-centric culture that’s typical of almost all U.S. cities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After being ignored, and then laughed at, we’re now at the stage — if you recall the Gandhi quote — where the opponents to safe streets are fighting back. They want to make sure that our Central avenue, currently an uncrowded four-lane road, stays that way (even though the speed limit is 25 MPH).  Ironically, I think it’s the same people that are against providing for other forms of transportation who also complain about too much traffic (by &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; drivers, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Our local advocacy group &lt;a href="http://www.bikewalkalameda.org/"&gt;BikeWalkAlameda&lt;/a&gt; started a petition — both an online petition and the old-fashioned type — to show that there is support for safer streets for people of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/185431-1431192149-wide_med.jpeg" alt="185431-1431192149-wide" width="300" height="150" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you live in, or near, the town of Alameda (or even if not!), I invite you to &lt;a href="http://www.thepetitionsite.com/185/431/429/speak-up-for-safe-streets-in-alameda/"&gt;add your name&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 16:37:33 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/pedestrian-cyclist-petition.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>California’s water waste is awful — but my idea to stop it may be counterproductive.</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/californias-water-waste-is.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week I was down in Southern California, and I was astonished to see lush, green lawns all around me, at least in the town of Pasadena where I spent most of my time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering that we are in the middle of a record-shattering drought in California, I couldn’t believe my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So with a bit of image-searching in Flickr, my own iPhone pictures, and some inspired snark, I put together two hypothetical “public service announcements” that I wished would exist, to get people to realize how destructive and wasteful it is to be watering your lawns this year.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/drought-psa-1.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/drought-psa-1_med.jpeg" alt="California, stop watering your lawns dammit! Worst drought in 500 years, and is anybody paying attention?" width="450" height="347" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a few days ago, I happened to read &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17331349-think-like-a-freak"&gt;Think Like a Freak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the third in the &lt;em&gt;Freakonomics&lt;/em&gt; book series by Levitt &amp;amp; Dubner. And I came upon a story that explained how public service messages just like this one, which draw attention to the behavior you want people to avoid, actually ends up &lt;em&gt;increasing &lt;/em&gt; the bad behavior.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They discuss a &lt;a href="http://www.psychologicalscience.org/pdf/cialdini.pdf"&gt;study by Robert Cialdini&lt;/a&gt; where they found that the signs &lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;in Arizona’s Petrified Forest National Park asking people not to steal pieces of petrified wood actually &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;increased &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;their theft.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item blockquote-container wide center"&gt;
						&lt;div style="" class="graphic"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;p&gt;Your heritage is being vandalized every day by theft losses of petrified wood of 14 tons a year, mostly a small piece at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
								
							&lt;/blockquote&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I guess that means that pointing out to Californians how they are wasting water is just making it worse. So we need to come up with something that actually works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But still, it’s fun to dish out the snark, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/drought-psa-2.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/drought-psa-2_med.jpeg" alt="My oh my, what a lovely lawn - worst drought in 500 years, and is anybody paying attention?" width="450" height="347" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 12:52:56 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/californias-water-waste-is.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Srsly, we need to put a stop to Geneio/InstallerMac</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/stop-geneio-installermac.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of last night, I can now say that over the last year, I have had to go to great lengths to extracate the horrible &lt;strong&gt;Geneio/InstallerMac malware&lt;/strong&gt; off of every single Mac in my immediate &amp;amp; extended family (except, thankfully, my own.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess for the basic Mac user, the alerts that InstallerMac puts up look innocuous and even helpful. Nobody remembers how it got installed. It might have been masquerading as an update to Adobe Flash in at least one instance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at &lt;a href="http://www.macissues.com/2014/04/23/how-to-detect-and-remove-genieo-for-mac/"&gt;the steps&lt;/a&gt; that are required to really remove everything that this malware leaves on your system&lt;a href="http://www.macissues.com/2014/04/23/how-to-detect-and-remove-genieo-for-mac/"&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; it’s clear that this stuff is &lt;em&gt;insidious&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in September of 2014, I submitted a bug report (&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;18193924) to Apple begging them to do something about this.  No response yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Doesn&lt;/span&gt;’&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;t it seem like Apple should take this kind of thing seriously? Isn&lt;/span&gt;’&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;t that what &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201940"&gt;XProtect&lt;/a&gt; is supposed to help us avoid?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;If you have a developer account and can get to &lt;a href="https://trello.com/b/xMnnolDa/server-migration"&gt;bugreport.apple.com&lt;/a&gt;, why not submit your own bug report?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 15:10:34 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/stop-geneio-installermac.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Since U Been Earworm</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/since-u-been-earworm.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/chekov_ceti_eel_med.jpeg" alt="Chekov getting an earworm " width="450" height="215" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been infected with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earworm"&gt;earworms&lt;/a&gt; from time to time. Usually they go away, for me, after a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alas, Kelly Clarkson’s 2004 breakout hit “Since U Been Gone” has been invading my consciousness for weeks, perhaps even months.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center"&gt;
						&lt;div class="Movie graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.YouTubeElement --&gt;
								&lt;div class="YouTubeElement"&gt;
									&lt;div class="video"&gt;
										&lt;iframe allowFullScreen="true" frameborder="0" id="youtube" mozallowfullscreen="true" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/R7UrFYvl5TE?rel=0" title="YouTube video player" webkitAllowFullScreen="true" width="450" height="253" class="graphic"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
									&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.YouTubeElement --&gt;
							&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;(No, I didn’t listen to this video as I embedded it here!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why that song? I have absolutely no idea. It’s not even listed on Billboard’s list of the top forty earworm songs. (OK, no such thing, but really this chart ought to exist!)&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;To quote the Electric Light Orchestra song, &lt;em&gt;I can’t get it out of my head.&lt;/em&gt; Even the peaceful vistas of Yosemite National Park last week didn’t cure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently, scientists are saying that you can push an earworm out of your head by &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/science/science-news/9950143/Get-that-tune-out-of-your-head-scientists-find-how-to-get-rid-of-earworms.html"&gt;solving a mental puzzle&lt;/a&gt; like an anagram. That’s all well and good, but I usually don’t have a collection of anagrams with me to work on while I’m walking the dog or washing the dishes or driving/riding somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least while I’m working, I can usually listen to my own choice of music to keep the earworm away. But heaven help me if I’m reading a book and it’s quiet around me. Here comes Kelly, again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One technique my brother suggested to me many years ago was to mentally sing to yourself the late-1980’s TV show “It's Garry Shandling's Show.”&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center"&gt;
						&lt;div class="Movie graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.YouTubeElement --&gt;
								&lt;div class="YouTubeElement"&gt;
									&lt;div class="video"&gt;
										&lt;iframe allowFullScreen="true" frameborder="0" id="youtube2" mozallowfullscreen="true" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/8cWbkWTYwTw?rel=0" title="YouTube video player" webkitAllowFullScreen="true" width="450" height="253" class="graphic"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
									&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.YouTubeElement --&gt;
							&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it works.  But after 25 years, I’m getting a little bit tired of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anybody else have any suggested treatments for a case of earwormitis? Hopefully something milder than electro-shock therapy but even that’s tempting if I could erase that song from my brain!&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 09:43:24 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/since-u-been-earworm.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Grateful rants</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/grateful-rants.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At last week’s &lt;a href="http://cocoaconf.com/yosemite"&gt;Yosemite&lt;/a&gt; conference, Michael Lopp closed out the sessions with an inspiring talk about writing.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first wide center"&gt;
						&lt;div style="" class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content HTMLElement"&gt;
								&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for unblocking the writer in me &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rands"&gt;@rands&lt;/a&gt; - what a perfect way to end &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/cocoaconf?src=hash"&gt;#cocoaconf&lt;/a&gt; at Yosemite! &lt;a href="http://t.co/sqR5JAbdVo"&gt;pic.twitter.com/sqR5JAbdVo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gautam Godse (@gautamgodse) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gautamgodse/status/591331377531850755"&gt;April 23, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
							&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of his three suggestions for &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to write about was to rant about something. (The other two, IIRC, were to clearly explain something you know and to express an opinion.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ranting is great. It's sure to get the creative juices flowing as your blood boils over thinking about the &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/10/8181531/cia-tagets-apple-xcode-encryption"&gt;CIA hijacking Xcode&lt;/a&gt; or the state of the health care system in the US or the continued hazards in &lt;a href="http://fukushimaupdate.com/"&gt;Fukushima&lt;/a&gt; or the wasteful water management practices of California agribusiness in the face of our crisis-level drought.  And if you can write about these things, and spread understanding of knowledge that might improve the situation, that’s great. If we didn’t have people writing, blogging, tweeting, talking about these issues, they’d just be swept under the rug. (In fact, many important issues still are largely ignored by the public.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But often ranting (usually on social media, not so much in long-form writing) ends up just complaining and spreading negativity.  Like that crying baby in the airplane a few seats back, or having to wait for the dishwasher repair dude too long, or the bad service you got at the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me, all that seems to do is to amplify the negativity for yourself, and spread negativity to others. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me it seems like the people who complain a lot are the ones who seem to always have these things happen to them. They guy who rants about babies crying in the movie theatre?  It seems to happen to him a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;. It’s like the complaining attracts more negativity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Yosemite, one of the presentations — I think it was the one by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jaimeejaimee"&gt;Jamiee Newberry&lt;/a&gt;, who talked about her “&lt;a href="http://www.jaimeejaimee.com/31days31people/"&gt;31 days 31 people&lt;/a&gt;” project of expressing gratitude — reminded us to focus on what’s good, and be grateful as a way to be happier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I’m personally going to modify Lopp’s&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt; advice to rant, and come up with a type of rant that&lt;/span&gt;’&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;s not negative! How about ranting with gratitude?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m considering some grateful rants to post in the days or weeks ahead. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 11:47:14 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/grateful-rants.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yosemite: A State of Mind</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/yosemite-a-state-of-mind.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mac developers and Mac enthusiasts probably equate “Yosemite” with the 10.10 version of the operating system; most others in the world equate the word with California’s gorgeous, dramatic park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last week, I was privileged to firmly place myself in both camps, by attending the conference &lt;a href="http://cocoaconf.com/yosemite"&gt;Yosemite, by CocoaConf&lt;/a&gt;.  Their tagline of “The Apple Conference with a View” sure wasn’t kidding.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/img_7462_med.jpeg" alt="IMG 7462" width="450" height="337" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conference wasn’t a technical conference at all.  And yet I think I learned exactly what I needed to learn, both from the presentations and in between them. (And I’m not just talking about 10-minute bathroom breaks.  There was a break between the morning sessions and the evening sessions where groups of us might go for an easygoing interpretive or photographic walk about the valley floor, or a vigorous climb up the &lt;a href="http://www.yosemitehikes.com/yosemite-valley/mist-trail/mist-trail.htm"&gt;Mist Trail&lt;/a&gt; to Vernal Falls.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The talks at the conference were entertaining and profound. And while the presentations were conceived and delivered independently, the theme connections between talks were so strong that it felt like they were part of a planned network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The presentation by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/antichrista"&gt;Christa Mrgan&lt;/a&gt; blew me away because it had elements of Yosemite, iOS design, and personal perspective all rolled into one.  She walked us through the design of a hypothetical iPhone app about the gorgeous &lt;a href="http://www.yosemitepark.com/high-sierra-camps.aspx"&gt;High Sierra Camps&lt;/a&gt;, where she used to work for several summers. (I think that by the end of the talk, we all wanted that app to exist, and we all wanted to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; at the hike-in accomodations that she described.  Maybe the next CocoaConf Yosemite could be somewhere accessible only by hiking in, with equipment packed in via mule?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ihnatko"&gt;Andy Ihnatko&lt;/a&gt; (I’m imagining that the “H” in his last name might indicate aspiration — a puff of air, when pronounced, extrapolating from what we learned from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/savinola"&gt;Laura Savino&lt;/a&gt;) told us what he &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; thinks about the ten-thousand-dollar Apple Watch; his perspective  on the importance of &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; being constantly bombarded by information and distraction was echoed in many other talks as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jamesdempsey"&gt;James Dempsey&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.billboard.com/artist/6297050/james-dempsey-and-the-breakpoints/chart"&gt;Billboard-charting artist&lt;/a&gt;), surrounded by several breakpoints and conditional breakpoints (who played guitar and sang excellently), rocked the house with his über-geeky songs. I wish I had brought my guitar so I could jam along (though I could never hold a candle to the guitar skillz of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jdalrymple"&gt;Jim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brentsimmons"&gt;Brent&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dwiskus"&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s just a small sampling of the wonderful presentations. Oh, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rands"&gt;Michael Lopp&lt;/a&gt; inspired us all to start — or restart — writing. The result is manifested here; let’s see if I can keep it up.  Oh, thanks for the &lt;a href="http://www.zebrapen.com/product-category/brand/brand-sarasa/?filter_point-size=115"&gt;awesome pen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, the Yosemite conference was inspiring and amazing, both inside the building and outside of it. My thanks to the Klein family for organizing the event, the many speakers who were either old friends or, hopefully, will become new friends, and the many attendees I got to know (especially by following the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C4_(conference)"&gt;C4&lt;/a&gt; habit of sitting at a table with people you don’t yet know).  I raise my glass in a toast!&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/inside-cocoaconf-yousemite_med.jpeg" alt="inside cocoaconf yousemite" width="450" height="337" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;© &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/shtjRK" style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Fernando Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;, used by permission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 10:13:34 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/yosemite-a-state-of-mind.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yosemite’s “Mail Drop,” with plain text emails, considered harmful.</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/yosemites-mail-drop-with.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yosemite has a cool new feature “Mail Drop” which is really handy for sending large files without having to resort to file-sending websites or DropBox (or its non-Condoleezza-Rice competitors).  &lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/mail-drop_med.png" alt="Mail Drop" width="450" height="127" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Apple Mail detects a giant attachment, it will offer to send it via Mail Drop, which means that the file is uploaded separately to a temporary iCloud URL.  It will stick around for 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that if you use this technique, it’s possible that any actual &lt;strong&gt;textual&lt;/strong&gt; message might not be seen by the receiver of the email message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you send your email message as plain text — you might not even realize that you are sending a plain text message or a rich text message —or if the receiver’s email client shows them plain text instead of rich text — then ONLY the Mail Drop URL will be seen by the receiver.  Not your important message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example message I might compose.  (I use a monospaced font to display plain-text messages, but if you use a proportional font, it might be that obvious.)&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/source-email-message_med.png" alt="source email message" width="450" height="233" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The message transmitted doesn’t even &lt;em&gt;contain&lt;/em&gt; the text; it only contains the Mail Drop URL:&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/mail-drop-received_med.png" alt="mail drop received" width="450" height="73" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if you commit to never sending a plain-text message with Mail Drop attachments, and you deselect Mail’s preference “Use the same mesage format at the original message”, you are not out of the woods yet.  If the receiver is using a mail client that prefers the plain-text portion of rich-text messages, then the problem happens there too.  That’s because the plain-text portion of the rich-text message lacks any text besides the Mail Drop link. Here’s an excerpt of a rich text message’s raw source — note the text/plain segment containing only the URL.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/message-source_med.png" alt="message source" width="450" height="312" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a real concern! For instance, we use FogBugz for tracking support cases, and while I want to encourage people to use Mail Drop for sending us large files when needed, we need to go through a lot of hoops just to determine if their message had any useful textual content in it.  Because all we see in a message that included a Mail Drop attachment is a big honking URL.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/fogbugz_med.png" alt="fogbugz" width="222" height="108" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just a rant; I’ve reported this to Apple (radar 18756471).  Hopefully they take it seriously!  If you, dear reader, know about Apple radars, feel free to file a duplicate if you think it’s sufficiently annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 09:04:47 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/yosemites-mail-drop-with.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>TeamViewer: Handy for helping with Mom’s Mac</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/teamviewer-handy-for-helpin.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a family member or friend for whom you end up taking care of their Macs, you may want to share their screen and take over their computer so you don’t have to spend hours giving them instructions on what to do and asking them to read what it says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried using screen sharing with my mom, but her router wasn’t going to let that work. Messages.app didn’t let her share her screen for some reason.  But then she came across &lt;a href="http://www.teamviewer.com/"&gt;TeamViewer&lt;/a&gt;.  And it works really nicely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They way it works is that you both launch the app, and Mom tells you her ID and password; you enter her ID (and then her password) and you are on your way!&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/screen-shot-2014-10-22-at_med.png" alt="Screen Shot 2014-10-22 at 9.54.13 AM" width="450" height="403" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 09:50:17 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/teamviewer-handy-for-helpin.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ken Wood, 1932 - …2014</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/ken-wood-1932---2014.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;My father passed away yesterday after a long, losing battle with Parkinson’s disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;And yet, I already was saying goodbye to him in some ways for over a year. That’s why his ending date really wasn’t 2014.  Because his Parkinson’s took a bit of him away at a time, to where there wasn’t much left when his body finally finished its journey.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And though many reading this memorial never knew him — or don’t know me, for that matter — this is my memorial to Kenneth Herbert Wood.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood-younger.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood-younger_med.jpeg" alt="Ken Wood, younger" width="200" height="296" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These years have taken an especially hard toll on my mother, who could no longer care for him at home.  But even with my father at a care facility, she still had many duties to perform, while spending an unbelievable amount of money.  When &lt;em&gt;Dilbert&lt;/em&gt;’s Scott Adams published his &lt;a href="http://dilbert.com/blog/entry/i_hope_my_father_dies_soon/"&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; “I Hope My Father Dies Soon,” it certainly struck a nerve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I would visit him, at first he was mostly “there,” mentally. He even achieved some fame within the facility and made the &lt;a href="http://gooddaysacramento.cbslocal.com/video/8979655-sensational-senior-ken-wood/"&gt;local TV news&lt;/a&gt; with a feature on him, due to his talent at drawing amazing portraits of his fellow residents. (Somehow his shaking hands would calm down when he was drawing.)  But then he deteriorated more, mentally and physically. When I would see him, there would be some of the man I remember, but not much. And less each time. So over those months, I found myself saying goodbye to him, at least in my own heart. He was shrinking, reverting, losing memories and physical abilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, late last week, he took a major turn for the worse, and never woke up.  And I’m very sad that he’s gone, but it’s also a blessed relief that it is over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I try not to think of the recent months where his body, even his face barely resembled its former self. Instead I try to think of the hero that my father was, and replenish my mind with memories of before the Parkinson’s.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood_med.jpeg" alt="Ken Wood" width="200" height="200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My dad was artistically creative his entire life. As long as I can remember he had been drawing, mostly cartoon-style.  He would apply that talent to drawings he’d give as gifts to the kids, or make into personal greeting cards for friends, or wherever something graphical was needed, or in support of his work. He’d create advertisements for the local country newspaper and community events.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/marysville-clarence.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/marysville-clarence_med.jpeg" alt="marysville clarence" width="200" height="257" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was about 10, he started creating some children’s books. “The Pickle Machine”, “Exactly Like Me”, and “Jeremy Dingle” never were published — he tried but didn’t get any bites from publishers — but they delighted us and have delighted my kids as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another example of how the Parkinson’s took hold was related to one of his children’s books. I had made a color copy of “The Pickle Machine” for my nephew so that he could enjoy it too. But for reasons unknown, my dad decided to rework the story, and had grand plans for changing the story. Though he wasn’t able to draw much, he would obsessively redo parts of the story, having whoever was near him help him cut drawings out, re-write the text, and rearrange sections.  And yet nothing of what he was doing made any sense. It got to a point of mania. Finally, in a moment of clarity, he consented to putting the entire project away on a high closet shelf. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the original, unaltered version still rests in my house. I have no desire to keep, or even see again, the Parkinson’s remix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/cover.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/cover_med.jpeg" alt="cover" width="200" height="241" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was born, my parents owned a stereo shop back in the sixties, Woodland Stereo Center in Woodland Hills, California. (Yes, one of the brands sold there was Kenwood!) The picture below was taken shortly after I was born, if you notice the addendum to the main sign!&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/image027.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/image027_med.jpeg" alt="image027" width="200" height="271" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when I was about seven, my parents – from the generation too old to be considered hippies — got bit by the “back to the land” movement in the early seventies and decided to move from the suburbs of Los Angeles to the country in Northern California. I remember being driven around in our family’s blue VW van while my parents looked for a place to live and start a new life. Finally we found an 18-acre property in the Sierra Nevada foothills, completely undeveloped, and decided to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/cornfield_med.jpeg" alt="Cornfield" width="450" height="625" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And on that property, with the help of my mom and some neighbors — and as much as we could, the kids — he built a house. From scratch. And while it was never quite finished – we moved in way before there where amenities such as wallboard or plumbing or electrical outlets — I lived in the house my dad built until I moved away for college.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Though my dad was weakened terribly in his last years — it seemed like the Parkinson’s aged him by more than a decade within the span of a year or two — most of my memories of him were being incredibly strong. He had to be, as a forty-something-year-old homesteader. Carrying two five-gallon buckets of water uphill from a nearby stream, building barns and temporary quarters and then our house, hauling 10-gallon milk cans, my mother proudly called him the “homestead gorilla.” &lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/homestead-gorilla.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/homestead-gorilla_med.jpeg" alt="homestead gorilla" width="200" height="244" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ken never had a single career track — the farming never really made a decent living for us — but overall I’d say that his biggest strength was sales. Selling hi-fi’s and stereos, then after moving on from the farming, he’d done well with selling advertising, solar water heaters, encyclopedias (along with my mom in that venture), and so on.  A skill that I never could quite grasp, yet he excelled at it and thrived at it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His biggest love — besides his family — was music, though. His classical record collection — on LP and reel-to-reel tape; later on CD — was enormous. He enjoyed very little in the popular music genre, though he did have a weak spot for the lead singer of the Stone Ponies, Linda Ronstadt (who, as it turns out, is now afflicted with Parkinson’s). While he tolerated the music that his kids listened to growing up, it was Beethoven and Mozart and Schubert and Chopin on the stereo in my house growing up. And opera, which I never really could appreciate the way I eventually started appreciating orchestral music.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his last year or so, he had a small stereo and a modest collection of his favorite music with him at the “old folks’ home.” I’m glad he had his music to keep him company, though I don’t think he was really able to make use of the equipment for the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ken didn’t just listen to music during his lifetime. He was a singer — a tenor — who sang every chance he got. Growing up, I remember going to see him solo in Handel’s Messiah every year. While I never picked up a love for opera, I relish my memory of seeing him perform in Sacramento in the chorus there shortly before his diagnosis.  I have a cassette tape — I ought to digitize it — of some of his favorite classical songs that he’d sing.  (Schubert’s “Was ist Sylvia” for example, or his parody of “Granada” called “Granola”, a tribute to the crunchy cereal.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parkinson’s took away his singing and speaking voice, gradually, though sometimes there were little reprieves. I wasn’t there, but a couple of years ago, there was a memorial service for a friend, at a time when the disease had taken away most of his voice, where he found himself singing, full-strength, a song in tribute at the memorial.  For those who knew him there, it seemed like a small miracle. I wish I had been there for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also remember him acting — a talent that completely skipped my generation. But he loved performing in community theatre, and also created a one-man show that he would perform week after week at a local campground resort, where he would play the famed stagecoach robber Black Bart.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood-black-bart-newspap.png" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood-black-bart-newspap_med.png" alt="ken wood black bart newspaper" width="200" height="303" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, my mom found an old reel-to-reel tape that was labeled somewhat cryptically along the lines of “Baby Announcement.” Intrigued, but with no machine to play it on, I took it home. Some research found a service that would convert a reel-to-reel tape into MP3 audio. Taking a gamble, I ordered a digitized recording. What came back (over a file download) was a treasure. When I was born — I’m the oldest — my dad had come home from the hospital, fired up his tape recorder, and called the relatives to announce my arrival. Hearing his speaking voice at its full strength — he was younger than I am now, actually — was amazing. I could also make out the voices of my grandmothers through the phone. Later in the tape, interspersed with odd recordings of music and television, so I’m glad I kept at it — I found other recordings from my own early childhood that he made while he was watching me. Amazing. What a great vault of memories from my life, from a time when I was too young to remember myself.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood-with-me.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/ken-wood-with-me_med.jpeg" alt="Ken Wood with me" width="450" height="342" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My dad was an amazing man and a loving father. And I know we had a good relationship throughout the entire intersection of our lifetimes. And I will miss him terribly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And after all that Parkinson’s disease took from him, I’m glad that his journey is finally over.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/angel-by-ken-wood.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/angel-by-ken-wood_med.jpeg" alt="angel by Ken Wood" width="200" height="230" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 14:09:23 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/ken-wood-1932---2014.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Informal or Formal when localizing apps?</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/informal-or-formal-when.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I reported a bug report to Apple (Radar 13833235) reporting that there didn't seem to be any public documentation about how non-English localizations of Apple apps should address the user.  While English doesn't distinguish between formal and informal senses, other languages certainly do. I wanted to make sure that Sandvox and any future apps are doing it the right way.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Apple's reply in the bug report was to direct me to an &lt;em&gt;internal&lt;/em&gt; Apple-only web page. Not too helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I pointed that out, they didn't take any steps to solve the issue, but instead they apparently just copied the text for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/french-translation-services_med.jpeg" alt="french-translation-services" width="334" height="135" class="first narrow right graphic-container" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that's annoying — I know the official Apple style for this, but nobody else gets to know?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that's why I have this post. I won't copy the post verbatim, since I don't want to be copying their intellectual property. But a summary ought to be of some use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They sent me guides for French and German. Since these guides are not consistent with each other, I guess that means that if you are dealing with other languages, you have to figure out the right sense yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be formal — &lt;em&gt;vous&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;tu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;OK to use French expressions, but not slang&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unusual to greet users by their first name; use &lt;em&gt;Cher Monsieur&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Chère Madame&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Avoid personal pronouns; in English we might say "your battery"; French would just translate to &lt;em&gt;la batterie&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"We are direct and friendly … that's why we avoid the formal &lt;em&gt;Sie&lt;/em&gt; … and instead use the informal &lt;em&gt;du”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 17px; "&gt;OK, Wait!  So we use the formal in French but the informal in German?  Wow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use lowercase &lt;em&gt;du&lt;/em&gt; since you are addressing a group of people&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;But address educators with &lt;em&gt;Sie.&lt;/em&gt; (Probably not really applicable for app localization).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve noticed how Apple addresses its app users in other languages, feel free to mention that in the comments here. Perhaps this page will be useful for other developers.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 13:55:26 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/informal-or-formal-when.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Healthful Honey Harvest</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/healthful-honey-harvest.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've mentioned here &lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/honey-harvest.html" target="_blank"&gt;before&lt;/a&gt; that I have some beehives. (Here's a &lt;a href="http://www.gardeners.com/backyard-beekeeping/8529,default,pg.html?SC=XNET9014"&gt;nice article about hobby beekeeping&lt;/a&gt; in case you are interested.) My two hives that I had last year didn't make it through the winter, so I had to start anew this year.  I caught three swarms this spring; the first one I caught has been doing just amazingly well. After just three months, I was already able to harvest some of their honey reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just before leaving for vacation last month I noticed that they had two full "supers" (boxes containing 10 frames) were full of honey. So I gave them some more layers in their hive, so they had a place to put even more honey, then took off to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that I'm back, I finally had a chance this weekend to go harvest those extra frames.  Four of the frames weren't quite ready yet (the honey cells should be capped up with wax when the honey is ready to go), so I left them in the hive. That left me sixteen frames — about 3 times the small harvest I had last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I put Fleetwood Mac on "shuffle" on the iPod and got busy in the kitchen to get this honey out of those frames.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just for fun, and since it's easier to use the iPhone camera in the kitchen than it is when I'm out in my badass beekeeping suit with the bees, I thought I'd take some pictures to show how the honey is extracted from the frames that come from the hive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a "super" with most of the frames still in it. I'd already shooed the bees away, so I've brought this into my kitchen where fortunately I have a very large, easy-to-clean counter.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/img_5898_med.jpeg" alt="Sweet Home Alameda — Honey frames before extracting" width="600" height="450" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see, toward the top of the photo, the exposed side of one of the frames.  Each one of these frames holds about 3 pounds of honey. But it's trapped in there; each cell is capped with beeswax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using a special tool, I scrape the top layer of beeswax off. (This is the messiest part of the operation.) The scrapings (a mix of beeswax and honey) get saved for later.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/img_5900_med.jpeg" alt="Sweet Home Alameda — Removing wax caps from honey frame" width="600" height="309" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The honey that gets made depends on a number of factors such as what flowers were used and storage time. If you look carefully you'll see that the honey on the right edge (added later, I reckon) is a lighter color than the darker honey in the rest of the photo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I dropped three frames, uncapped-side-out, into a hand-crank extractor (borrowed from another beekeeper) that uses centripetal force to throw the honey out to the sides, where it drips down the stainless steel walls to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/img_5899_med.jpeg" alt="Sweet Home Alameda — honey frames in extractor" width="600" height="450" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a vigorous spin, I repeated the process with the other sides of the frames. After spinning out another set of three frames, the bottom was getting full, so it was time to pour the honey out into a five-gallon bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/img_5906_med.jpeg" alt="Sweet Home Alameda — pouring honey out of extractor" width="300" height="400" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time I got through the sixteen frames, that bucket was pretty full! If I had had any more to spin, I would have had to start a new bucket's worth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weird coloring is just little bits of beeswax that also got spun off of the frames.(I call it "oatmeal" because that's what it looks like to me.) It rises to the top, and can be filtered out or just scraped off the top after it has a chance to settle.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/img_5917_med.jpeg" alt="Sweet Home Alameda — bucket full of honey" width="300" height="400" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The total amount of honey in that bucket, from those 16 frames? &lt;strong&gt;A bit over fifty pounds&lt;/strong&gt;. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next step is to jar it up. The bucket has a spigot on the bottom, just like the extractor, so it's easy to fill up jars. I slap on my homemade label (Handmade "Sweet Home Alameda" label designed to resemble the Lynyrd Skynyrd logo) and the jars are good to go!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Go where? Well, so far my harvests have been small enough that it's just barely enough for the family and sharing with friends. This time, I may share with even more friends! I'm not quite ready to give up the software business yet….)&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/sweet-home-alameda-honey_med.jpeg" alt="sweet home alameda, honey jars" width="600" height="776" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 21:22:28 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/healthful-honey-harvest.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>WWDC Woes</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/wwdc-woes.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, none of my Karelia colleagues or I were able to get WWDC tickets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really agree with &lt;a href="http://bitsplitting.org/2013/04/25/end-wwdc/"&gt;Daniel Jalkut's analysis&lt;/a&gt;, but I have some more thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WWDC that I knew and love is gone. With only a tiny fraction of the people I know getting tickets, it means that WWDC will be a conference filled with strangers to me — and to each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure, there will be some parties, and maybe a chance to run into somebody you know, but the odds are against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe the problem is that when Apple Started WWDC, it made sense to have the entire &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; invited. These days, there are too many Mac and iOS developers in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seeing that the talks are going to be made available online, it's really the labs and the socializing that we will all be missing. But do all those need to be concentrated in a single week, in a single place?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if Apple made the sessions be online only, as Daniel suggestions, and come up with a series of regional conferences/labs around the world, based on developer population?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, this kind of thing has happened before. The developer 'tech talks' a couple of years ago. They've also had a few special, small "developer kitchens" in Cupertino, though that was before the masses started growing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why not just start up an annual program of "tech talks" which are staffed by DTS engineers and evangelists, touring the world constantly? They could function as mobile versions of WWDC labs — but just as importantly, there could be social aspects to the gatherings, so that fellow developers had a chance to eat, drink, and be merry with fellow developers in their local area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 17:21:59 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/wwdc-woes.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>You killed my father. Prepare to die.</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/you-killed-my-father.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;You've all seen &lt;em&gt;The Princess Bride&lt;/em&gt;, right? And you've memorized those immortal lines:&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first blockquote-container wide center"&gt;
						&lt;div style="" class="graphic"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;p style="font-style: normal; "&gt;Hello. My name is Inigo Montoya.&lt;br /&gt;You killed my father. Prepare to die.&lt;/p&gt;
								
							&lt;/blockquote&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18rcb_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Inigo Montoya. You killed my father. Prepare to die." width="450" height="253" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With an upcoming kids' production of Disney's &lt;em&gt;Mulan&lt;/em&gt; coming up in our household, we realized that Captain Shang gets to take revenge upon his father. And in this production, in final rehearsals, I've heard that there has been a line inserted, along these lines:&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18rei_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Captain Shang. You killed my father. Prepare to die." width="450" height="253" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What a great idea! I love it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then, I realized — and found with a little help from the Internets — that this line could be part of, well, a lot of movies and stories! (Especially Disney movies!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So wirthout further ado:&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r0s_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Harry Potter. You killed my parents. Prepare to die." width="309" height="163" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r4l_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Tarzan. You killed my father and mother. Prepare to die." width="450" height="263" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18rmb_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Vito Corleone. You killed my father. And this is for you." width="450" height="246" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18qz2_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Data. You killed my father. Prepare to die." width="450" height="344" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r2c_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Luke Skywalker. You’re about to kill my father. Prepare to die." width="450" height="253" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r2t_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Hamlet. You killed my father. Prepare to die." width="400" height="184" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r13_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. I’m batman. You killed my parents. Prepare to die." width="450" height="630" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r9l_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Ariel. You killed my mother. Prepare to die." width="450" height="269" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r85_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. Our names are Violet, Klaus, and Sunny. You killed our parents. Prepare to die." width="400" height="300" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r96_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Anakin Skywalker. You killed my mother. Prepare to die." width="450" height="350" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/18r36_med.jpeg" alt="Hello. My name is Simba. You killed my father. Prepare to die." width="450" height="377" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did I miss any?  &lt;a href="http://imgflip.com/memegenerator"&gt;Make some of your own&lt;/a&gt; and link to 'em in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 15:21:02 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/you-killed-my-father.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>USB Power Integrated into AC Wall Outlets</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/usb-power-ac-wall-outlets.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I ran across a product that you could install in your house to put in a convenient USB power plug (or two) into a wall outlet, going alongside the regular AC outlets (USA style).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After mentioning it on Twitter, I got a bunch of replies from my tweeps — and later, even a company representative from one of the available products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got recommendations for three different outlets:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://fastmac.com/usocket.php"&gt;U-Socket&lt;/a&gt;. Ports to the left of AC outlets. Standard (rounded) and décor (rectangle) styles.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newertech.com/products/power2u.php"&gt;Power2U&lt;/a&gt;. Closable ports on either side, in the center.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.leviton.com/OA_HTML/ProductDetail.jsp?partnumber=T5630-W&amp;amp;section=42298&amp;amp;minisite=10251"&gt;Leviton USB Charger&lt;/a&gt;. Two USB ports on top, in a décor style, replaces an AC outlet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/usb-charger-outlets_med.jpeg" alt="USB Charger Outlets" width="281" height="150" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All three seem to have sufficient power for charging your iOS devices. U-Socket claims 2.4A charging power; Power2U says 2.0A; the Leviton says 2.1A.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U-socket indicates that it won't drain power when it's not in use. The Power2U makes the same claim. I didn't find any similar claim about the Leviton. However the Leviton has a "smart chip which recognizes and optimizes the charging power of your device," so I'm curious how that compares to the others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All outlets are 15 Amps for the AC power, though the Power2U promises a 20A version coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these seems adequate, so it may come down to form factor if you are choosing the brand. Unfortunately, the place where I want to install one of these is on a double-wide (4-outlet) box, so my choices are limited. I may end up using a Leviton, since it doesn't require a custom wall plate, and I could put the Leviton and a standard décor outlet into the box and use a standard double-wide décor plate. Another alternative would be to carefully cut the holes needed in a stock cover from your local little-box hardware store, or use a 3-D printer if you are geekier than me!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before making your choice, make sure that the outlets will fit in your electrical box! This has bitten some people, apparently!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An alternative, not requiring any rewiring, is this add-on &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Slim-Wall-Plate-Surge-Protector/dp/B0065KWUCK/"&gt;surge protector with USB ports&lt;/a&gt;. It has 2.1 Amps for fast charging. It also provides three AC plugs. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One interesting issue came out of the discussion: Data privacy. If you install one of these in your own home, it wouldn't be a worry, but would you plugin your iPhone or iPad into such a device in a public place, where &lt;em&gt;conceivably&lt;/em&gt; there could be a device hooked up to suck out your contacts. It is interesting how data and power are delivered on the same plug, so unless you have some sort of adapter or extension cable that you know only will let power (and not data) through, you would be putting your data at risk if you plugged your device into an untrusted port.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to @bbum, @jnouwen, @simX, @mjtsai, @bjh, @weldon, @ddribin, @siegel, @McCarron, @AbbiV from FastMac, and anybody else I missed here, for their advice!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 11:34:22 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/usb-power-ac-wall-outlets.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prefiltering Your Mail to Keep Your Inbox From Filling Up</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/prefiltering-mail-inbox.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/mail-filter_med.png" alt="mail filter" width="120" height="84" class="first narrow right graphic-container" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've long been a fan of the "&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done"&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;" way of life, especially when it comes to my email. I've managed to keep "Inbox Zero" fairly consistently for a few years now, and it's very liberating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One aspect of email that has long bothered me, however, is how usually my inbox — well, really multiple inboxes; I have several email addresses — are usually filling up with messages that I don't want to read when I'm on the go. If I'm away from my desk, or taking a weekend or vacation away, I really don't need to see GitHub updates, bank updates, company newsletters, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had tried using mail rules in the past to filter some messages into specific email boxes, but then when I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; at work, these filters just seem to get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm trying out a new system now that I wanted to share with both of my readers. It's still in progress, but so far it's working out nicely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's how it works. I have a machine running Mail all the time, checking frequently and applying rules, twenty-four hours per day. The goal is to get as many non-essential messages out of the inbox as quickly as possible so that when I do check email, from wherever I am, the inbox contains only messages that I probably &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to see. Usually that means personal communications from people, where I may want to answer them even if I'm not at my desk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've created mailboxes for — and filters to fill — these four categories:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work, Daily&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work, Weekly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Personal, Daily&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Personal, Weekly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The filters are usually based on either matching a specific subject or sender. If you have a system of signing up for newsletters with special email addresses (e.g. including a "+" in the address) you might be able to match by that criteria. No matter the specifics, the goal of the rules will be to decide how important a message is in the context of work or personal emails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a message is something I probably should read soon &lt;em&gt;while I'm working&lt;/em&gt;, it goes into "Work, Daily." That becomes, essentially, a secondary inbox while I'm at my desk. I'll check it several times a day when I'm working. But if I'm not at my desk, I won't be seeing these, since there isn't any point in them until I get back to my desk!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examples of these in my case, as a software developer, include GitHub notifications, build script output, notifications of case assignments from Fogbugz, daily software promotional emails, notifications when somebody posts to a topic I'm subscribed to on our forum, payment notifications, and so forth. Critical notifications, such as server problems, should definitely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be put into this category; I want to hear about such matters even if I'm on the go, so I can do something about it, even if it means delegation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work-related emails that aren't time-sensitive at all can go into a "Work, Weekly" mailbox, for checking every few days (or once a week) &lt;em&gt;when the opportunity arises&lt;/em&gt;. Newsletters from other companies, technical mailing lists, etc. might go into this category. Anything that I could easily miss for a few days should go here.  (On my mail rules for the "weekly" messages, I also have the messages marked as "read", so that they aren't beckoning me. Otherwise, I might be tempted to "whack-a-mole" and read the weekly messages prematurely, when I should be paying attention to other matters!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I then have my personal daily/weekly rules that work along the same principles. "Daily" emails include daily news bulletins, bank/stock alerts, Netflix notifications, etc. — where I want to know about it that day, not several days later.  Messages that can wait a few days include bank statements, kickstarter updates, political updates, newsletters, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, this has worked for me quite well. Since I'm just starting with this program, I'm often finding messages that slip through, so I need to tweak my filters from time to time. But after just a few days with this, I'm finding that my inbox barely has any messages in it, and it's easier to process my "daily" or "weekly" messages efficiently when I'm in the right context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to give this a try?  Any tips or suggestions on improving this?  Please let me know in the comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:58:33 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/prefiltering-mail-inbox.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gifts that Last (Plus, why Gustave Caillebotte is now rolling in his grave)</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/gifts-that-last-plus-why.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month, an article called &lt;a href="http://dcurt.is/the-best"&gt;The Best&lt;/a&gt; made its way around the Blogosphere. Not long after, a rebuttal called &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtcrime.org/blog/the-worst/"&gt;The Worst&lt;/a&gt; offered a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn't place my finger on why I didn't really agree with either point. OK, I probably veer toward the "I don't need the ultimate dinnerware" camp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But one must live at either extreme, given a choice? How about something in the middle, where you don't feel the need to seek out the brand that will impress all your friends and readers of your blog, but something that will actually &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; for a while so you don't have to keep buying replacements?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, I would find that I would need to buy a new pair of slippers each year, with the previous year's purchase having completely fallen apart from wear and tear. (I have a home office — they get a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of use!) That got really tiresome, so I looked into an alternative. I bought a somewhat more expensive pair of slippers from &lt;a href="http://theleatherworks.net/"&gt;these guys&lt;/a&gt;. That was three winters ago that I bought them, and guess what‽ They are in almost perfect condition today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, I bought slippers for the rest of the family. Of course, they are still kicking as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next example: You know those cheap umbrellas you buy for $3-$5 when you are caught in the rain? Yeah, I've gone through a lot of those. They don't last long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/umbrella_med.png" alt="umbrella" width="125" height="108" class="first narrow right graphic-container" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I also have a really cool umbrella I got as a gift, featuring &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paris_Street;_Rainy_Day"&gt;Paris Street; Rainy Day&lt;/a&gt; by Gustave Caillebotte. This was three or four years ago, maybe more. I walk in the rain a lot (when it's too wet to be on a bicycle) and this umbrella has seen a lot of use. And it's still in perfect condition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(I'm guessing that &lt;a href="http://www.artistgifts.com/la-salva-umbrellas/rainy-day-paris-umbrella7419.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is the umbrella that I got, which has lasted so long. There are appear to be several variations available for sale over the web, but the one pictured here seems to match the tip and handle of mine.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Point being, that &lt;strong&gt;sometimes it is worth a bit of extra cost if the item you buy is actually going to last for a while.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In related news:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was recently wondering what would happen if the couple in the Rainy Day painting had that same umbrella? This little hack made in &lt;a href="http://www.flyingmeat.com/acorn/"&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; was the result.  My apologies to the heirs of Caillebotte.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/rue-de-paris.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/rue-de-paris_med.jpeg" alt="Rue de Paris" width="588" height="450" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 16:38:54 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/gifts-that-last-plus-why.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>13 Tips, Summarized, on Setting up a Secure, Resettable Password Database</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/13-tips-secure-password.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I ran across an awesome blog post from earlier this year on web database security: "&lt;a href="http://www.troyhunt.com/2012/05/everything-you-ever-wanted-to-know.html"&gt;Everything you ever wanted to know about building a secure password reset feature&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since reading online tales of some of the horrible things that crackers have been able to do to get to people's account information, I thought that this was a fascinating set of guidelines on building a database of users and passwords the right way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original article is worth a read, especially if you are working on any database of users, but it's a long read. Here is my brief summary for your convenience (and perhaps someday for my future reference):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;In your database, store passwords as a one-way hash with a salt that is also stored in the table.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don't send the user's password to them.  (Doing the above will obviate that.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If user requests a password reset, send an email regardless of whether that email is associated with an account.  (If it's not an account email, you can tell them that in the email, NOT on the web page.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the password reset mail, send a time-limited URL with a unique code that allows them to go in and set a new password; do NOT send a new password. (See point 2).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consider using a CAPTCHA on a password reset form if automated attacks are an issue.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;To avoid problems where somebody's email is compromised, a password reset might contain secret questions.  If you do this, make sure that they are concise, specific, diverse, hard to discover, and constant over time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Secret answers should be stored encrypted in the database. (Hashes are problematic if they need to be verified by a person.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consider two-factor authentication.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do not allow password reset via username, only email address&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In your password reset emails, indicate the IP address of where the reset request came from.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Notify the account owner via email when account information is changed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do lots of logging (but without sensitive information) to help uncover malicious behavior.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do not lock out the old password from working until the new password information is completely verified.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, a good overview. Hopefully more and more account providers follow this kind of advice — I cringe when I see my password sent to me over email in clear text!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 14:59:58 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/13-tips-secure-password.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Making Crisp Retina Icons for your App</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/making-crisp-retina-icons.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, heeding warnings from Apple that we would need higher-resolution icons, we got into the habit of asking our icon guy to make double-size images (sometimes even quadruple-size) when we needed to create a graphic that was better created as a bitmap rather than a vector graphic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So when the MacBookPro with Retina Display came out, we thought we were in pretty good shape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we had to throw out a lot of our work and backtrack. Seeing our icons on the actual retina display, we realized they needed to be a bit sharper, especially when it came to crisp details like lines and outlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we had been doing was essentially doubling any single-pixel lines from the source image. So if we had an icon with a rectangle bordered by a single pixel, the double-size icon would have a retina bordered by a two-pixel-wide line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So instead, we had the icons re-done so that the lines were a single pixel in the retina version. But to compensate for the fact that this might not be as bold as the original, we made the line a bit darker (or more opaque, which usually ends up being the same thing).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take for example this icon in Sandvox's inspector: &lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/page_inspector-orig_med.png" alt="page inspector-orig" width="16" height="16" class="first" /&gt; On the left is the image enlarged to match the new retina size; on the right is the retina image. (Both of these are enlarged so you can easily see the pixels.)&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/inspector_med.png" alt="inspector" width="472" height="212" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's another one. The non-retina "objects" toolbar icon on the left; the right is the retina version with the single-pixel lines.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/objects_med.png" alt="object toolbar" width="640" height="246" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story is that it's important to pay attention to how a double-resolution image will be perceived on a retina display!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Here's an interesting example from Apple that somebody pointed out. iTunes 11's "Up Next" icon looks like a bullet list on a standar displays, but actually shows numbers on a retina display!)&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;div class="not-first-item graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/itunes_list_med.png" alt="itunes list" width="140" height="52" /&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 17:24:19 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/making-crisp-retina-icons.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Amazing Photo of Nelson Mandela</title>
			<link>http://gigliwood.com/blog/amazing-photo-of-nelson.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I'm working on Sandvox, I tend to have a pile of random images I use for testing things. Here's one I ran across a few days ago. It's one of my absolutely favorite photos. Not for any artistic reason, but the whole story behind it makes me smile.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="first graphic-container wide center ImageElement"&gt;
						&lt;div class="graphic"&gt;
							&lt;div class="figure-content"&gt;
								&lt;!-- sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/mandela.jpeg" class="imageLink"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gigliwood.com/blog/_Media/mandela_med.jpeg" alt="Mandela" width="581" height="478" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
								&lt;!-- /sandvox.ImageElement --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you haven't seen the 2009 film &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invictus_(film)"&gt;Invictus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, or the read the book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.com/0143115723"&gt;Playing the Enemy: Nelson Mandela and the Game That Made a Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, do it soon. Both are very well done, and tell the amazing story behind this photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
					
				&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 12:53:54 -0800</pubDate>
			<guid>http://gigliwood.com/blog/amazing-photo-of-nelson.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
 	</channel>
</rss>